Oh no, this is a title that makes me
want to read it because again biases
confirming my biases. Also, last week I
did a full seven days in the tower doing
nothing but vibe coding with cursor and
also regular coding and also complaining
about AIS and then also loving tab. Very
complicated relationship right now. But
I have a problem here. April 1st. I
don't know where this is going to go.
Like is this going to be a good article
or is this going to be another article
in which I get sad about reading because
it's April 1st. Let's find out. TLDDR. I
choose to make using AI a manual action
because I felt the slow loss of
competence over time when I relied on it
and I recommend everyone to be cautious
with making AI a key part of their
workflow. I still think I'm going to get
I still think I'm going to get AI uh
what's it called? April fooled here any
moment. Here we go. We're going to get
ready. Uh in the late 2022, I used AI
tools for the first time. Even before
the first version of Chad Jippity uh in
2023, by the way, the first time using
Copilot, I still remember. I still I I
talk about this all the time is the
magic moment. Magic moment. Absolutely
magic. One of the best moments I've ever
had. Very, very magic. In 2023, I
started using AI based tools in my
development workflow. Initially, I was
super impressed with the capabilities of
LLMs. The fact that I could just copy
and paste obscure compiler errors along
with C++ source code and be told where
the error is cause uh caused felt like
magic. Yeah. Yeah, that does feel like
magic because forget C++ errors. Yo. Yo,
if there's one thing I hate more in life
than C++ errors, it's signing into my
terminal, right? Like there's few things
I hate more, but that's one of them. Um,
once GitHub Copilot started becoming
more and more powerful, I started using
it more and more. I used various other
LLM integrations right in my editor,
using AI as a part of my workflow. I do
want to say though that GitHub Copilot
sucks. It just does. It's not good. It's
not been good. It's not being good. It's
not looking good. It doesn't feel good.
It doesn't make me happy. It's just
mostly bad. It predicts many two lines.
It's often just gross. It's just wrong.
But I've been converted. I've always
said I've always said this for a long
time. I think the best AI coding like
assist isn't these question and asking
vibe coding approaches. I think they're
just horrible. The best assist is a
really good autocomplete. And before I
ever even used cursor, I we were I even
kind of made my own little quick version
in uh VS or Vim just to kind of feel how
it would be in a neoim feel what it was.
And I was like, "Okay, that's pretty
cool." But then when I use cursor, it
actually has such a good version of
copilot. Their version of copilot tab is
so good. It's totally worth at least
giving a try, but your skills will
immediately atrophy. It's always the
problem about offloading stuff. The
moment you offload, you just don't think
about things as more. Anyways, in the
late 2024, I removed all LLM
integrations for my code editors. I
still use LLM occasionally, and I do not
think AI can be used in a way that is
very beneficial for many
programmers. Generally agree. So then
why don't I use AI powered code editing
tools? Uh Tesla FSD from 2019 to 2021 I
drove a Tesla. Bros just out there just
telling you what he's driving flexing on
us kids. 2019 Tesla days. Those are
pretty popular days a Tesla. Though I
would never make the same purchase
again. Not for political reasons, just
because the cars are quite low quality,
very overpriced, and a hell to repair or
maintain. Yeah, I've heard the I've
heard the repairing is insane. By the
way, when I was in the Bay Area, like
the 2014, 2015, 2019, it was a flexa to
have a Tesla, right? When I got my
Tesla, I started using the full
self-driving FSD anytime I could. It
felt great just to put the car on FSD on
the highway and zone out a bit.
Switching lanes was as simple as hitting
the turn signal, and the car would
switch lanes. Driving for me was getting
to the highway, turning on FSD, telling
the car to switch lanes every now and
then, and listen to music and podcasts
while zoning out. If you drive a car
often, you'll know that when you're
driving on the highway, everything sort
uh sort of happens automatically.
Keeping your car in the lane at the
right speed becomes a passive action. It
does not require the type of focus that,
for example, reading a book requires.
It's the same type of focus that walking
requires. It happens in the background
of your mind. Fair. It's just really
annoying. So far, he's making a great
case for me to want to get a
self-driving car. I hate driving. I just
hate driving. Driving is hypnosis, dude.
It's Dude,
it's In the period of from 2019 to 2021,
I exclusively drove my Tesla for longer
rides. After 2021, I went back to
driving regular cars, and making the
switch was definitely not what I
expected. Driving on the highway
required my full attention for the first
uh for the first month or so. I had to
relearn keeping the car in the middle of
the lane without thinking about it.
Being reliant on Tesl Tesla's FSD took
away my own ability to go into
autopilot. Okay, that's actually an
interesting argument. So I think the
argument he's trying to make is that
tasks in which we do regularly become
background tasks like walking. There's a
lot of like hidden things that you do
that you don't realize you're doing or
the calculations that are required that
your body just does naturally for you.
And if you take that ability to do that
away, the natural easy thing that used
to be easy becomes hard. Okay, that's a
good Hey, it's a good it's a it's a very
good basis to build a good argument. I
think I think this is Yeah, literally
muscle memory. Well, it's actually like
spinal memory to be completely fair.
Everyone talk about it, but uh this is
actually a really I think this is
actually a pretty great basis for an
argument. My experience with AI code
editors working with AI powered code
editors was somewhat similar. Initially,
I felt that I was comp uh I completed
work a lot faster when assisted by AI.
The work I was doing most of the time
was not super complex and AI felt like
putting my Tesla on FSD. I could just
guide the machine to do the work for me.
Yeah. Yeah. In my free time, I started
working on side projects on my personal
account on my work device. Uh on this
account, I did not have access to
copilot and other cool fancy AI tools.
This is when using AI started to feel
very similar to te uh the Tesla FSD
story. Yeah. Now that I got done using
cursor for a week, honestly, going back
to Neil Vim, sometimes I'm uh sometimes
I'm in here and when I start going here
and I go like this. All right. Uh or I
go uh param and I'm like gosh just
autocomp completed already for me. Yeah,
I have a snippet but then I have to go
like number and I have to go number and
then I have to like go number, right? Oh
my gosh, just I already know what you
want. You know what I want? I know what
I want. Just make it happen, right? And
if I use co-pilot, I could get that back
on. But co-pilot's also super annoying
everywhere else cuz copilot's like
actually. And it's always wrong like 95%
of the time it feels like and just makes
me feel like I'm going to go bonkers. Oh
my gosh. It just I just want I just I
just hate I just hate using it. It's
like pair programming with the most
annoying person in the universe. Uh you
just get to see their thoughts just all
the time. All right. Anyways, I felt
less competent at doing what I was quite
basically software development than a
year or so before. All of a sudden, it
made very clear to me how reliant I had
become on AI tools. I don't think this
is a bad thing, right? Like I'm not sure
if it's a bad thing. I have to think
about this more, but I'm not quite
positive if the if just programming is
the end- all beall. I think that you
lose a lot of really keen sense of
what's going on when you don't type it
yourself. And I think that you lose a
lot of mastery and you lose a lot of
just like familiarity with the API and
you lose like but I could also argue
that LSP in some sense makes the exact
same thing happen that the LSP itself
also makes you lose some of that quality
that when it comes to being a really
good programmer. I think they're on a
near same level. Not quite. They're
they're like a different in they're a
different in magnitude not a difference
in kind. Uh anytime I defined a function
I paused in my editor to wait until the
AI tools would write the implementation
for me. It took some effort to remember
what the syntax was to write a unit test
by hand. Ah yes the old co-pilot pause.
So this is a real effect for those that
are using uh AI regularly. Try uh just
try writing without it for a second. Try
writing without copilot and you'll
realize that you just like stop and your
brain just like literally turns off. LSB
for faster navigation, by the way, is
very, very good. I like that. You like
literally turn off your brain and it's
just super annoying and you're like, why
am I turning it off all the time? Uh,
with my work, AI started to become less
useful over time as well. Not only did
it take out the uh out the fun for me,
but I started to feel a bit insecure
about making some implementation
decisions myself. Oh, interesting.
Outsourcing the decisions to the AI
seemed a lot easier, but sometimes the
AI couldn't figure things out even with
the best prompts. uh it was quite clear
that because I did not practice the
basics often I was less capable with the
harder parts as well. So this actually
was an argument within um the there was
a paper by Microsoft and Carnegie Melon
about the effects of turning off
critical thinking and uh using AI and
they made this really great argument. I
forget what the there's an author that
talks about to do the hard things
requires you to do the easy things
millions of times. And so one of their
kind of core arguments of the paper was
that by stopping doing the easy things,
the harder things become harder, which
is actually a pretty interesting
argument. The paper took literally 30
pages to say like a two sentence to say
two sentences. It was absolutely
mind-numbing to read, right? It was
like but it was like a really uh it
comes from Whitehead. It comes it's
actually let's see it's an old argument.
And it comes from Whitehead. Uh well,
the real analysis of it. Yeah. So,
there's like this idea that if you don't
make a thousand little decisions that
are easy, you're not going to be able to
make one hard decision. And that's all
there is to it. And it's it he's kind of
I think he's saying that without saying
that
uh with my work, AI started to become
less Oh, I already read that. Uh the
loss of finger uh finger spits and goil
uh finger spits and goil. Yeah. is a jam
and term literally meaning fingertips
feeling. Oh yeah, the feelings go feel
and meaning intuitive flare or instinct
which has been adopted by the English
language as a lone word. It describes a
great situational awareness and the
ability to respond most appropriately
and tactfully. Interesting. So it's like
a it's like a form it's like a form of
muscle memory but in the realm of
competency. To play an instrument very
fast, the only way to play it uh is to
play very slow in repetition over time.
I think this is I think this often with
AI plus programming. Interesting. Yeah,
finger
feel. We do we just call is this what we
call uh muscle memory otherwise known as
touch in the NFL? Yeah, finesse. And I
think in sports ball we call it finesse.
Who who no one uses this word. I think
we just call it finesse. Right. Hey
finger spits. Thank you. The only way to
chop fast is to start chopping slowly.
Yes. Correct. Defing seniority is a very
tough thing. Though in my opinion, a lot
of being a senior is in soft skills.
When it comes to the technical hard
skills, a lot comes down to finger
spits. I don't even know how to say that
word. The longer you work with a
language framework or codebase, the more
you develop this kind of intuition of
what the correct approach is. Yeah, I
think that's all true, right? Like
anyone who's worked in a larger
codebase, it's like mysterious, large,
and annoying at first and becomes easier
and nicer as time goes on and then
eventually it becomes easy to work in.
And then soon you're off running fast.
And that's just like, you know, we I
think people often can call that thing
like tribal knowledge. People try to say
you need to document everything, but
there's a certain level of documentation
that just stops working. Like you just
can't do it. It no longer works in that
realm. It's like, yeah, intuition, it's
good. It's a good thing. It feels good
to be an expert at something. Um, the
gut feeling of something feels off
slowly turns into a feeling of this is
what we should do. This developed
intuition is not just an architectural
level level. A big component is in the
lower level details. When you use
pointers or what type of pointers,
whether you use asserts or checks, what
to pick from the standard library when
multiple options are available. Those
senior C++ programmers still can't seem
to agree on this. This intuition is what
I was slowly losing when relying on AI
tools a lot. And this is coming from a
lead developer. When I see a lot of hype
about vibe coding, I can't help but
think, how do you exactly expect to vibe
code your way to a senior? Where where
will you get the skills? uh from to
maintain and extend the vibe coding code
base when the AI tools are down or have
become too expensive. I think I mean I
think there's probably a level of
intuition finger spits finger sprites
and there's a bit of finesse that
probably comes with uh prompts and
context that you also can probably grow
on when it comes to prompting. There are
people who are better at prompting than
me. Uh Cockorn, don't even try that with
me. Uh L take it's always becoming uh
it's always up and becoming cheaper. Uh
lately things haven't been cheaper.
Okay, I'm just saying Jippy 45 is really
expensive. Okay, Sam Alman was promising
is promising me 10x cheaper per year and
6 months after he said that it got 100x
more expensive. Okay, this is stupid. I
want a 10x. Sam wouldn't lie, would he?
He did he did just get done raising 40
billion. So sure I'm now he's I'm sure
he's tweeting now like wow man this
shit's expensive. We got a lot of money
to fix these problems now. Don't you
worry. Eggs went up almost 10%. Yeah. Or
10x. Yeah. It's crazy. Uh even with
larger context windows, more computing
power, reasoning models or agents, there
will be things that AI won't be able to
do. Over time, the AI tools will get
more and more powerful. Sure. But when
you receive a Slack message that uh the
website works fine, but the app is down
in production. I tried locally and there
it works fine. Nothing in sensory
either. Good luck getting an a AI agent
to fix this for you. Maybe it can, maybe
it can't. And when the AI agent can't
figure it out, will you reply, "Sorry,
cursor doesn't get it. We'll uh we'll
prompt more
tomorrow." I do love that, David. Sorry.
We'll prompt again tomorrow. I'm kind of
out. I'm kind of, you know, my creative
prompt juices are kind of out for the
day, so I'm just going to prompt again
tomorrow. Okay, dude. That's such a
great phrase. I want to use this all the
time. You can get by without these
tools. Yeah, you most certainly can. Uh
people that say that like you're being
left behind, I think are incorrect. You
know, I haven't used tab or cursor until
just last week. And after using it just
for one moment, maybe like what an hour
and a half, I became a very big expert
at exactly how tab works and where it
works and why it works and when to use
it. And so it's just like I don't think
I just don't think there's like this
so-called barrier to entry where it's
like if you're not profiting now, you're
never profiting again. Okay, so you're
saying they're going to get better all
the time? Yeah, they're going to get
much better. We're going to get way more
integrated. It's going to be completely
different here in like three years.
Okay. So, what am I learning
now? Checkmate, atheist. Uh, you can get
by with these tools. Uh, you're late for
for things. Uh, sometimes it feels like
you have to use AI or be out of a job in
6 months. We've been hearing the 3 to 6
months away now story forever. Uh, over
two years at this point. Uh, when I got
my Tesla in 2019, I paid
6400 for functionality that was supposed
to arrive in 3 to 6 months from now. And
the functionality is still not present
the way it was promised over five years
ago. Self-driving cars is like the
greatest look into the future. Look at
self-driving cars. We've been promised
self-driving cars for a long, long time.
Right now, it is unlikely that letting
AI do your coding work for larger
projects than a university project. When
working on legacy systems or larger
projects in enterprise or when you need
to work with a and consult a lot of
dependency internals like I do with
Unreal Engine, AI tools will often not
be able to make things work. When you
need to work with internal DSLs, uh
tools or frameworks, good luck getting
LLMs to generate uh useful output for
industries. You can't even use AI tools
at all for a multitude of reasons. Yeah,
first off, let's go backwards that list.
By the way, this is really important. If
you solely depend on this, you're like
not getting a job in medical, finance,
government, banking, like there's a
whole slew of industries that just like
AI not allowed, right? And I'm sure that
will change over time and things will
change and blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah, but right now like
that's just like a closed door for you.
So, it's a good thing to re recognize
and I don't know. Let's see. Uh, Goldman
is big on AI tools now for dev. Yeah.
And so that could change in banks, but
I'm not sure how fast or quick that's
going to change. Uh, second off, this is
really, really good. I think the biggest
takeaway you can take from this sentence
is stop making DSLs. Just use
Lua. Just Lua. Lua easy, DSL hard. Every
time I make DSL, I make sad. Like that's
it. That's it. That's it. That's that's
all that's all I have to say for that.
For some things, you really should not
want to rely on AI when implementing
authentication systems like JWT signing
uh or RBAC. Adding uh and it should be
secure to the prompt won't make it
secure if it's been trained on GitHub
code that had CVEEs. By the way, there's
an if statement in here that's not
useful and also is a very very exciting
part about the future. Security is going
to be a very needed field for a long
time because the reality is where is
this code coming from? It's coming from
GitHub. Where are we discovering all
these security issues? They're always in
software that is open source that people
use. Why? That's because like security
issues are just a natural part of
programming. So, if everything's trained
on this, what's going to happen? It's
just going to make more of it. It's just
going to replicate it. Statistically
speaking, it makes security problems for
you. Everybody's just stealing my
terrible code. Uh, when it comes to
security, you should be the person who
is responsible and understands this
fully. Critical systems should be
written and reviewed by humans. here.
Actually, a great example. NextJS last
security uh bug. This was just up here.
Where was it? Their low-level alerting
had a really great one, but it's very,
very simple. Here's how effectively it
works, right? It says it lets attackers
bypass authentication. Uh maybe this
will be it. But here, let me let me just
give you the the skinny of how it works.
It's very very simple. there exists some
sort of like X uh trust me bro header
that you could just add to a request and
if the middleware saw trust me bro it
would just go uh yeah we don't need to
run authentication on this request and
that was just out there the whole idea
was this uh the idea why this thing
exists to begin with uh dev's doing
security am I right the reason why this
existed is that you have some sort of
HTTP request coming in right uh and Then
it goes into your system. Well, then you
have middleware that goes off and does a
request cuz everything is like
microservices and all this stuff to go
and see are you authenticated? That
authentication needs to make a request
that needs to pass through middleware
again apparently like apparently this is
how people have things set up. So then
it would then do this thing forever. So
their way around that was x trust me bro
and bro would be like ah trust you and
you just pass right through the
middleware and just keep on going or you
pass right through the authentication uh
middleware like that's it was SSA. Yeah.
Super secure
authentication. Trust me, bro. True.
True. Right. That's insane. I mean, it's
it's a thing. It's just it it just
happened. Um, is it a is it is it is it
that crazy? It's really not that crazy.
There it is. X middleware sub request.
That's the trust me, bro. Right.
Everybody was clapping when someone
introduced this optimization. Exactly.
When someone solved this recursive
middleware request thing, everybody
clapped. Beautiful. Absolutely
beautiful. There's there's about 10 more
dozen examples of this uh of the same
type of attack. Oh, it exists
everywhere. Good answer. Good answer.
Right. And so it's just like remember
that was just fixed like a week ago in
Nex.js. That means there is a nonzero
chance that if you're doing security in
an AI's programming, things can happen.
You know, you might just accidentally
eat that snake's tail. When it comes to
security, you should be the person who
is responsible and understands this
fully. I've done that and I've also
introduced security problems. Critical
systems should be written and reviewed
by humans. And if we are heading to a
situation where one AI agent writes the
code and another reviews the
autogenerated PR and then another AI
agent deploys the code, we will see a
huge spike of security issues soon.
Absolutely. Like absolutely. By the way,
that was not a knock against Nex.js. Uh
for those that are wondering, this is
just why it's hard. Like security is
hard and things that seem like
reasonable solutions to somebody that
doesn't have the context of how things
work will go, "Wow, that's a reasonable
solution." Because you know, whoever
made that change, there was probably
somebody else that reviewed it and said,
"Oh, that's a good idea. Good answer,
Todd." Right? Like Todd made it like I'm
a genius. And then somebody else was
like, "Todd's a genius." Right? Like
there's multiple people that let this
thing go through. Who knows how many,
right? So, uh, let's see. As an XJS, uh,
NexJS user, it should have been a knock
on NextJS. It's not It's not a knock on
Next.js. It's just like that's the like
security is hard. Security it. Uh, what
what was it? Uh, Androl from the Black
Tower, Wheel of Time, book 14. Uh, boom.
Yeah, we're citing more Wheel of Time.
I'm just about to finish Wheel of Time.
Okay. uh someone uh the uh Pava was with
him and she's like all men are ignorant
and he said yes that's because not all
men can know everything and so everyone
is ignorant of something which is
awesome which is an awesome line you
it's just it's just simple ignorance on
security right it's not it's not it's I
it's not even a knock against him right
where I draw the line I still use AI
sometimes I think it can be a great tool
when used wisely I draw the line at
integrations I keep AI fully separate
from my code editor. So that's actually
my opposite take. If you're going to use
AI, you might as well have it in your
editor. Uh all of the context I add
manually. I intentionally keep the
effort required quite high. So it is uh
so it decentizes me. Interesting. Okay.
That's because you can't help yourself.
Okay. Yeah, I guess that makes sense. Um
let's see. Examples of where I use AI
for work include convert these go tests
instructs to tests in a map. Fair.
Convert this calculation to SIMD. This
is nuts. Uh, and when the content type
is application zlib, decode the body, I
have to set up some custom instructions
to only give me the code that has
changed and to give me instructions for
adding it. This way, I'm still the one
making the changes in the codebase. Just
approving a git diff is not enough. I
want to manually add the code myself.
Only then do I feel confident to sign
off it or off on it and take
responsibility for it. Yeah, I mean
there there is something to that where
you can get lost in the sauce of a git
diff. That's fair. You could get lost in
the sauce. That's that's fair. That
happens. It's easy to like That's why
when I do a review of code, I think it's
easier to do a review code on GitHub
than in my editor. Like even though I
know how to do diffs on my editor, I
know how to do all those things. I can
definitely look at stuff. I just look at
it differently when I'm on GitHub. Like
my my mind changes. I have this very
intense kind of thought process because
I've trained myself when I'm on a
website. I somehow just review it better
than when I'm in my editor. When I'm in
my editor, I just don't review it as
well. I don't know why. I can't explain
why. I don't think it's a UI problem. I
think it's a mentality problem for me. I
think it's just simply when I look at
it, I've adopted the mentality of I'm
reviewing and a lot different like
internal like it's like driving on the
highway. I don't think about it anymore,
but it's like it's like this automatic
process that comes up. I'm not even
trying to say it's good or bad. I'm just
saying it's just I get it. Another great
use case for AI is learning. I often
have questions that are quite uncommon
as I have a few very niche interests.
Turns out adding net code to a custom
game engine using ECS doesn't have a lot
of learning resources. What has worked
for me is asking the AI to explain
pieces of code like explain this
assembly code. Explain what this shader
does. Which books go in depth about
resolving client server desyncs in game
engines? The AI seems to struggle with
these sometimes. I'm getting mixed
results, but the results are still much
better than search engines. Yeah, I do
like uh AI as a search engine. I think
that I dude RIP Google or not even RIP,
you know, rest in rest in poop Google, I
dislike you. Uh I don't like Google at
all. Uh I will even use it for this
article though I'm not right. Let's see.
Though not for writing content, but for
checking like AI as search is pretty
great. I like AI. AI search very good.
Another benefit of using AI this way is
the cost. No unnecessary API calls,
manually managing context, and more
control over the LLM settings. I use a
desktop application with a bunch of
different LLMs hooked up to it. I have
used it daily for the last three months
or so and in total I have consumed
around $4 in credits. I don't want to
add let's see I do want to add that with
some things I am more strict on my
personal website. I don't have any AI
generated content whether that's text or
images. I don't like the AI generated
images or art personally for various
reasons and I think AI generated text
lacked character. It feels very flat and
boring when something is created by
humans. it it to me has more value than
uh when it's create created by AI. Yeah,
that's fair. I think a lot of people
feel that way. So, I I'm I'm on this
team. I'm I'm on that team. AI is
stealing uh artist jobs is brain rot.
It's not I I don't think it's brain rot.
I think AI is going to take artist jobs
for sure. I think a lot of people like I
can't tell you how many people that just
need like small icons or potions for
their games and stuff like that and
they'll just generate it uh and just
kind of walk away with it. especially a
lot of indie stuff, stuff that's only
ran by one person. Totally can see that
consuming a lot of like what used to
have to be, well, I won't have good art
unless if I have an artist. Uh I I think
it's going to happen, but again, I think
that's that's because it's it's again
measuring the wrong thing, which at the
end of the day, it's about measuring the
output. Like we could have generated all
the
towers, all the tiles, all the dirt and
everything for our tower defense game,
but instead we had Adam see Ununice. You
may have heard of him. amazing pixel
artist guy come and join us at the tower
and he was there he was talking he was
coming up with ideas he was making great
art the art is so coherent through all
the pieces of art that it's much much
better and that's because it's not
created in a vacuum it's created
holistically from one person so there's
like a theme and a feel that's really
really amazing and this is of course me
not touching on any of the topics around
like copyright licenses and all that I
think that's going to be an entire like
I think the next five years we will see
some pretty serious
issues when it comes to AI and that
don't steal Adam from releasing his
game. I only used him for a week or 5
days. So, it's very very little and he's
already in America and he was already
traveling for GDC. So, it's not it's
it's not a lot, right? I think I think
uh AI is going to have a lot of a lot of
problems uh when it comes to uh when it
comes to stuff. It's theft. It's fraud.
Plain and simple. Many AI arguments are
not technical. They are legal. Some
people see some people companies
understand and only uh let's see only
the stick or some people's company only
understand with the stick. I'm not sure
if that's true. I'm not sure how much of
it is legal or not legal. Uh I think
that there's plenty of public uh public
domain images that you can train off of.
There's also uh AI programs that are
trained off of artists who opt in and
give their styles. Um and so like that's
that's a thing people do that. And so
that's real. Also, I think this is I
think this is a very interesting
argument that we have to come to terms
with, which is legal don't matter to to
China, right? There's there's a lot of
things that you're going to have to kind
of think about in the future. I don't
think it's a I I think there's a lot of
reckoning and a lot of laws that are
about to happen. I just don't know what,
how, where, and how do you approach it.
It's just more very interesting. All
right. It is also worth noting that
there are more things to think about
than efficiency and productivity. It's
also about doing what you love. If you
love coding, keep doing it yourself,
even if the computer might be better at
it. True. And if you like making
products and you don't really like
coding, then it's probably better to
trade-off to use something that makes
the code for you. Right? In 1997, Deep
Blue won the chess match against the
world chess champion Gary Kaspor uh
Kasporov. Yet people still play chess.
When it comes to programming, I' I'd say
that I program for the same reasons that
people still play chess. Though chess
and software development are very
different with chess being much more
limited in
scope. True. Uh I love just dunking on
chess. Um, I think it is good to keep in
mind that sometimes we can do things
just to enjoy them. True. My advice to
new program, I like this statement, by
the way. This is a good statement. You
can just do things because you like
them. There doesn't have to be some sort
of monetizing outcome to it. And you
know what the best part is? Sometimes
monetization happens at the end. Like
good things happen at the end, but it
doesn't have to be the strict motivation
for it. My advice to new programmers,
don't become a forever junior who lets
AI do all their work. If you want to
become a programmer, learn to program
yourself. Be curious. Just let's see.
Put in the time and effort to learn how
things really work. Yeah. TJC course on
boot.dev. My HTTP course on boot.dev.
Just saying. Good ways to start learning
some backbone stuff and how things work
in the layer below that. It really pays
off. Learning how everything works under
the hood. And using that is amazing.
Just keep learning. Don't be a prompt
engineer. Even if you call that
engineering, believe me, it's more fun
to be competent. I love this term.
That's by That's a DHH one. DH DHH. DHH.
DHH. Yep. Boom.
It is just more fun to be competent.
Let's go.
DHH. Let's go. He's a fact. Fact of
life. It is more fun to be competent.
Called it. Oh yeah. That's because that
is like that was like the greatest it
was the greatest interview of all time.
DHH is just a just a legend, right? Just
an absolute legend. Even though AI might
be smarter than you. I don't think it is
that I don't think you can use the term
smarter. It's not smarter. It's not
dumber or smarter than you. Never
blindly trust the AI output. Don't build
your whole workflow around it. Sometimes
try to work uh without it for a few
days. I like the airplane test. If you
can't program what you're doing on an
airplane, I you don't know it. Like if
you can't turn off the internet, sit on
an airplane, sit uncomfortably, be taken
completely out of your workplace, work
on a little laptop computer, and you
can't be efficient in work. I don't
think you have a good setup. The better
at programming you are, the more AI will
get in your way for the more complex
work. If you learn to code now, keep
building your skills instead of letting
AI do all the heavy lifting. You are
capable of fixing the messes that vibe
coding is now creating. I don't want to
sound elitist, but if you don't want to
learn to go beyond vibe coding, maybe
coding isn't for you because positions
where all work can be done by vibe
coding are the ones that will be
eliminated first when AI becomes more
powerful. Also true. Good trueing right
there. That's actually a pretty
hilarious observation. Vibe coding vibe
coders will be the first to be
eliminated as they get more as they get
more powerful. if and remember if you
cannot code without AI you cannot code
also great statement but I do mean that
the airplane thing I I don't say that as
like some sort of jer like oh you just
don't understand how to program it's
because your best thoughts will come
when you are limited and you're just
sitting there and you're just thinking
nothing's interrupting you nothing's
writing code for you nothing is doing
anything for you it's just you your
computer you're trying something you're
thinking you're trying something you're
thinking it's completely blank of all
other distractions and all of a sudden
you'll come up with like your best ideas
and that's because you've actually had
time to allow inspiration to happen. You
cannot be inspired when you're
constantly interrupted, right? It's just
like the constant forever. It just
doesn't work. Honestly, I I' I've always
hated that. I've always hated that
argument. Oh, well, just you got like,
you know, the
syntax is like the like what what do you
mean? If syntax is the barrier for you
to understand
programming, it's like brother, the
semantics is way harder. It's way, way,
way, way harder than the syntax.
Universally, all modern languages give
you great output when you goof something
up. Okay, shots fired at CO. I That's
why I said modern. Okay, this dude got
one guy hard. I did, but I but it's just
like such a common one guying. It's such
a common one that people say this
constantly like, "Oh, something about
syntax." And I always just get so blown
away that syntax is the barrier. Like
syntax is just not the barrier. It's not
hard. Anyways, conclusion. When you're
using AIS, you are sacrificing knowledge
for speed. Sometimes it's worth making
the trade-off. Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
You should know when to do that. I think
this article is a little heavy-handed on
when you should and shouldn't do it. Um,
I think that you just got to figure out
what you like the best and the reasons
why you program. At the end of the day,
I don't think there's a solid answer. I
don't think there's like I don't look
down on the person that just vibe codes
everything. I just wouldn't I just
wouldn't work on their projects. And if
someone's like, "Here's $1,000. Could
you fix a bug?" I'd say no. I just I I
don't want to be I don't I don't even
want to be a part of it. Unless if I can
prompt my way also and spend uh 30
minutes doing it or else I don't want
anything to do with your code. Like your
code is trash and I don't want anything
to do with it. That's it. Right? I don't
want to have to deal with your crap.
Right? I'm more on the implication side
of things. as long as you're long as at
the end of the day the code looks good
and you've done a good
job like I don't care how you made it
right. Uh though it is important to
remember that even the best athletes in
the world are still doing their basic
drills for for a reason. Yes. Yes. This
is good. Uh the same applies to software
development. You need to practice the
basics to be able to do the advanced
work. You need to keep your axe sharp.
We are still a long way out from AI
taking over our jobs. A lot of companies
are creating FOMO as a sales tactic to
get more customers and or raise money to
show traction to their investors to get
another round of funding to generate the
next model that will definitely
revolutionize
everything. AI is a tool. It is not good
or bad in itself. It's what you do with
it. You know, they say it's not the size
of the tool that matters. It's not the
size of the parameters that matter. Uh I
do think it can be a great tool as long
as you are not reliant on it for your
workflow. Uh make sure you still can
work effectively without it. Make sure
you don't push code to production that
you don't fully understand and don't
think of AI as a replacement for your
own thinking. Stay curious, keep
learning. I think this is one thing that
uh cursor did really really well which
is like I think Devon made the big
mistake and I think cursor did not make
the big mistake. Cursor goes engineers
are going to be around. We're going to
make it easy to use AI. Devon said,
"Engineers aren't going to be around.
We're going to replace them. We're going
to make it easy for you to to use LLMs."
And they're two distinct schools of
thought. The Devon one, I think, is
built and predicated on this idea that
AI is going to improve at this really
crazy rate. Cursor is built on this idea
that increased conveniences will make
you use it more, but you are still the
one in control. I think Devon ultimately
is not going to be successful unless if
there is an
intense change in the power of LLM to
the point where it actually makes it
possible to vive code uniformly for all
problems or B cursor is going to be the
success because it has the good tabbing
it has
uh it has better integration and a lot
of people are going to just rely on it
for a lot of
coding right Devon got replaced by AI
unironically Devon got replaced by AI.
All right. Hey, I like the article. I I
really I I really did like the uh the
Tesla one and just the emphasis on a lot
of small pract like a lot of practicing
the little things make you good at the
big things. And I think that that's the
shortcut a lot of people want to find. I
think this is just like you see it in
kids. If anyone in here has raised kids,
it's the number one problem of a lot of
kids is that the small things they don't
want to do. It's the big thing. People
always want to do the big thing. Why can
I not do the big thing? Why can I not
lead the big thing? Why can't I do that?
You know, but if you watch Euro Dreams
of Sushi, the people that he brings on
to help make the world's greatest sushi
have to spend three years making rice.
Just making rice. That is it. Because to
understand the process in the most
intimate possible way, you have to do
something over and over and over and
over and over and over and over again
until the point where you just get it so
deeply that it's like a completely
different understanding of what you get.
And so therefore, it's a message lost on
a lot of people because people don't get
that there's layers of knowledge.
There's not just knowing the thing.
There's like a deeper knowing the thing
and why it's good, but not just simply I
like some things I know about
programming I cannot write into a book.
You cannot write into a book. It just
exists. It exists within you. And even
if you try to write them down, it's
never going to come out correct. the
name is I feel like I was halfway
through my sentence and I stopped. Yeah,
it's intuition is the is the term you're
looking for, but it's like it's it's
more than intuition. It's it's also it's
like it's these sequential logical jumps
with the gaps being filled in by
intuition. So, it's not just simply, oh,
I think this is better. It's like this
is better because if I think about this
next thing, I think this will be better
here and then if I think about the next
thing, the next thing. It's like playing
chess on top of programming that makes
it end up so good. It's not just one
simple jump. It's the many jumps in
between. Right. Anyways, it's finger
spits and fragle. Yes, exactly.